

SYSTEM SECURITY ENGINEER · SOFTWARE ARCHITECTURE RESEARCHER · SOFTWARE REPOSITORY MINER

731 Lexington, New York City, NY 10022, U.S.

□ (+44) 7521-437-785 | ■ dle50@bloomberg.net | ★ lemduc.io | 🖫 lemduc | 🛅 lemduc | 🕥 lemduc

Summary_

Blends research experience in Software Engineering, Data Mining, and System Security with diverse and practical trainings in the software industries of Vietnam, S.Korea and U.S. to offer solid skills in software design and development. Experiences include (1) mining software repositories/big data, (2) system security, (3) architecture design, recovery, and analysis, (4) software product line engineering.

Education

University of Southern California (USC)

Los Angeles, U.S.

PHD IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, SOFTWARE ARCHITECTURE RESEARCH GROUP (SOFTARCH)

Aug. 2013 - July. 2018

Advisor: Prof. Nenad Medvidović.

GPA: 3.87/4.00

Pohang University of Science and Technology (POSTECH)

Pohang, S.Korea

MSc in Information Technology Convergence Engineering, Software Engineering Lab (SELab)

Aug. 2010 - May. 2012

Advisor: Prof. Kyo Chul Kang

GPA: 95.9/100.0

Hanoi University of Science and Technology (HUST)

Hanoi, Vietnam

BSc in Information Technology (Magna Cum Laude)

Aug. 2005 - May. 2010

• Advisors: Assoc. Prof. Huynh Quyet Thang (HUST), Dr. Martin Nordio (ETH Zurich) GPA: 8.07/10.00

Work Experience

Bloomberg L.P. New York, U.S. & London, U.K.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

July. 2018 - PRESENT

- · A member of the System Security team at Bloomberg
- Maintain and extend Bloomberg Single Sign On system.
- Manage the access control of Bloomberg's computer system

NEC Laboratories America, Inc.

RESEARCH INTERN - COMPUTER SECURITY GROUP

Princeton, New Jersey, U.S.

Analyzed activity logs of PCs in the company's internal networks and extract patterns of safe activities.

- Built different prediction models for those patterns.
- Implemented the approach and integrated into Automated Security Intelligence (ASI) system of NEC.

Veritas Technologies LLC

Culver, California, U.S.

May. 2017 - Aug. 2017

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN - EV.CLOUD PROJECT, PLATFORM TEAM

May. 2016 - Aug. 2016

- · Applied topic modeling and machine learning techniques to intelligently suggest retention policies for customers' emails.
- Implemented and verified the proposed approach on Enron dataset using Spark, Hadoop, Cassandra, and Spring Framework.
- Was selected to present at VERITAS Cutting Edge 2016.

Samsung Research America

Irvine, California, U.S.

RESEARCH INTERN - ADVANCED PRINTING SOFTWARE LAB

PHP DEVELOPER & ASTERISK PBX ADMINISTRATOR

Jun. 2015 - Sep. 2015

- · Completed the end-to-end scenario of extracting UP (Unified Interfaces of Samsung Printers) variability information from an actual MFP (Multi-Functions Printers), representing this in a UP variability model, editing this information, and using it to configure a running simulator instance.
- This involved design and implementation using different technologies: OSGi, EMF, Eclipse plug-ins, REST-ful webservices, UI development.

Dasan Handysoft Seoul, S.Korea

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aug. 2009 - Jun. 2010

Sep. 2012 - Jun. 2013 • Designed the server architecture of HandyUC 5.0, a platform providing various types of communication to enterprises, including email, instant mes-

saging, and video conferencing.

Implemented communication protocols of HandyUC, including XMPP protocol, Handysoft's legacy protocol, and a Http-based protocol.

HDC Media Vietnam Hanoi, Vietnam

• Developed a movie website based on Joomla platform to provide video contents to customers.

· Maintained and adapted Asterisk PBX system of the company to meet the company's requirements.

OCTOBER 18, 2021 Duc M. Le · Curriculum Vitae **Publications**

Architectural Archipelagos: Technical Debt in Long-Lived Software Research Platforms

Mandrid, Spain

MARCELO SCHMITT LASER, DUC M. LE, JOSHUA GARCIA, NENAD MEDVIDOVIC

May. 2021

Proceeding of the International Conference on Technical Debt (TechDebt 2021)

Architectural Decay as Predictor of Issue-and Change-Proneness

Stuttgart, Germany

DUC M. LE, SUHRID KARTHIK, MARCELO SCHMITT LASER, NENAD MEDVIDOVIC

March. 2021

Proceeding of the IEEE International Conference on Software Architecture (ICSA 2021)

Arcade: an extensible workbench for architecture recovery, change, and decay evaluation

Sacramento, U.S.

MARCELO SCHMITT LASER, DUC M. LE, JOSHUA GARCIA, NENAD MEDVIDOVIC

Nov. 2020

 Proceeding of the ACM Joint Meeting on European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering (ESEC/FSE 2021)

An Empirical Study of Architectural Decay in Open-Source Software Systems

Seattle, U.S.

DUC M. LE, DANIEL LINK, ARMAN SHAHBAZIAN, NENAD MEDVIDOVIC

May. 2018

Proceeding of the IEEE International Conference on Software Architecture (ICSA 2018)

Recovering architectural design decisions

Seattle, U.S.

Arman Shahbazian, Youn Kyu Lee, Duc M. Le, Yuri Brun, Nenad Medvidovic

May. 2018

• Proceeding of the IEEE International Conference on Software Architecture (ICSA 2018)

A Large-Scale Study of Architectural Evolution in Open-Source Software Systems

POOYAN BEHNAMGHADER*, DUC M. LE*, JOSHUA GARCIA, DANIEL LINK, ARMAN SHAHBAZIAN, NENAD MEDVIDOVIC

Jun. 2017

• Empirical Software Engineering (EMSE) Journal

Toward a Classification Framework for Software Architectural Smells

Duc M. Le, Daniel Link, Yixue Zhao, Arman Shahbazian, Chris Mattmann, Nenad Medvidovic

Feb 2017

• Technical Report at USC Center for Systems and Software Engineering

Architectural-Based Speculative Analysis to Predict Bugs in a Software System

Austin, U.S.

DUC M. LE, NENAD MEDVIDOVIC

May. 2016

· Proceeding of the 38th International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE), Doctoral Symposium track

Relating Architectural Decay and Sustainability of Software Systems

Venice, Italy

DUC M. LE, CARLOS CARRILLO, RAFAEL CAPILLA, NENAD MEDVIDOVIC

Apr. 2016

• Proceeding of the 13th Working IEEE/IFIP Conference on Software Architecture (WICSA)

An Empirical Study of Architectural Change in Open-Source Software Systems

Florence, Italy

Duc M. Le, Pooyan Behnamghader, Joshua Garcia, Daniel Link, Arman Shahbazian, Nenad Medvidovic

May. 2015

• Proceeding of the 12th Working Conference on Mining Software Repositories (MSR)

Validating consistency between feature model and its implementation

Pisa, Italy

DUC M. LE, LEE HYESUN, KYO C. KANG, KEUN LEE

Jun. 2013

Proceeding of the 13th International Conference on Software Reuse (ICSR)

Patents

Method for creating a feature model from legacy system source code

Korea

KYO CHUL KANG, HYESUN LEE, DUC M. LE Patent number: KR101290847B1

• Patent link: https://patents.google.com/patent/KR101290847B1/ko

Research Experience.

Architectural Change and Decay in Open-source Software Systems

Los Angeles, CA, U.S.

SOFTWARE ARCHITECTURAL RESEARCH GROUP, USC

Feb. 2014 - July. 2018

- Reversed architectures of over 800 versions of 23 open-source systems, totaling over 120 MLOCs.
- · Found evolution trends related to architectural changes in software systems, rate of architectural decay occurrences, correlations among implementation decisions and architectural changes.
- Use implicit problems, e.g., architectural- and code-smells, in combination with explicit problems, e.g. reported issues and bugs, to provide an accurate, systematic and in depth approach to predict potential system problems, particularly bugs.
- Cooperated with Huawei USA in a study of how to adapt the company's codebase to architectural changes in new Android versions.

Duc M. Le · Curriculum Vitae OCTOBER 18, 2021

Privacy Preserving in Distributed Computation

Los Angeles, CA, U.S.

SOFTWARE ARCHITECTURAL RESEARCH GROUP, USC

May. 2014 - Aug. 2014

- Studied sTile, a tile-based architecture, which tackles the problem of distributing computation onto cloud, while providing probabilistic guarantees that agents compromising parts of the cloud wouldn't be able to learn the private data and the nature of the computation.
- Deployed and evaluated a prototype of sTile on several main cloud services (Azure, EC2, Google Cloud).

Impact Analysis of Software Requirement Change based on Feature Relationships

Pohang, S.Korea

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING LAB, POSTECH

Sep. 2012 - Feb. 2013

- Reversed feature models based on variation points and variants embedded by C preprocessor.
- · Verified consistency between designed models and reversed models and provided refactoring advice.
- Integrated into VULCAL Workbench, a CASE tool that supports software product line engineering.

CloudStudio - Enabling distributed projects to produce software "on the cloud"

Hanoi, Vietnam

ETH ZURICH & HUST

Aug. 2009 - Jun. 2010

- Created the initial version of CloudStudio, an Integrated Development Environment (IDE) enabling globally distributed software projects and producing software "on the cloud".
- Developed the following features: project management, code editor, project compilation, group communication.

Honors & Awards

Best Paper Award, ICSA 2018	Seattle, WA, USA
'Thesis in Three' - Best Presentation Award, Doctoral Symposium, ICSE 2016	Austin, TX, USA
Awardee, ACM SigSoft CAPS Travel Support for attending ICSE 2015	Florence, Italy
Awardee, USC Doctoral Student Summer Institute Award	Los Angeles, CA, U.S.
Awardee, Vietnam Education Foundation Fellowship	U.S.
Best Poster Prize, 3rd International Symposium on IT Convergence Engineering	Pohang, S.Korea
Awardee, Certificate of Merit for Excellent Graduation Achievement	Hanoi, Vietnam
	'Thesis in Three' - Best Presentation Award, Doctoral Symposium, ICSE 2016 Awardee, ACM SigSoft CAPS Travel Support for attending ICSE 2015 Awardee, USC Doctoral Student Summer Institute Award Awardee, Vietnam Education Foundation Fellowship Best Poster Prize, 3rd International Symposium on IT Convergence Engineering

Skills

Programming Java (Proficient), Python, Linux Shell, PHP, JavaScript, C/C++

Frameworks SAML, OAuth2, Open ID, Spark, Spring, OSGi, EMF, GWT, Joomla, Liferay, Microsoft Azure

Databases MySQL, MongoDB

Others Agile Development, CI/CD, ŁTFX, SVN, Git, Asterisk PBX

Relevant Coursework

Software Engineering Software Architecture Software Testing Advanced Algorithms Artificial Intelligence Decision Support Systems

Machine Learning Natural Language Processing Advanced Operating Systems Database Systems
Information and Data Modeling
Information Security